homebase.co.uk 2019-09-27

# Privacy policy from Homebase Helping to Make Your House a Home | Homebase

## This Privacy Policy was last changed 31st August 2018

#### 1 - Who we are

We are HHGL Limited trading as Homebase (we/our/us) (Company number 00533033 with registered office address Witan Gate House, 500-600 Witan Gate, Milton Keynes, United Kingdom, MK9 1BA). This policy describes how we use your personal information.

We respect your privacy and value the trust you place in us when you share your personal information with us. This policy sets out how we, as data controller, collect, process, use and disclose your personal information, why we use it, with whom we share it, the rights to which you may be entitled and your choices about our use of your personal information.

This policy covers our use of your personal information arising from use of this website as well as registering for an account with us or buying / using our products and services. If you have any questions or need any further clarity please get in touch via email to [Data.Protection@Homebase.co.uk](mailto:Data.Protection@Homebase.co.uk) or via post to Head of Legal, HHGL Limited, Witan Gate house, 500-600 Witan Gate, Milton Keynes, Bucks, MK9 1BA.

#### 2 - Your information

**Data Collection and Usage**

We collect your personal data in a number of ways, for example, to allow access to this website, subscribe to our newsletter, receive information or mailings, to buy/use our products and services, make a comment, enquiry or contact our Customer Team and for other purposes set out in more detail in this section.

| What we collect | How we use it  
---|---|---  
1 | 

Information that you give us to make a purchase, subscribe to our newsletter, receive information or mailings, sign up for a prize draw or competition including:

  * Your contact details including: your name, address, email address;
  * Your bank account or credit/debit card details;
  * The product or service purchased

| 

We use this information, including to:

  * Provide our products and services;
  * Manage and administer prize draws, competitions and our services;
  * Process your order;
  * Take payment from or give you a refund
  * Help us ensure that our customers are genuine and to prevent fraud;
  * Send news on our offers, great value products and inspiring DIY projects.

2 | 

Information about the way you use our products and services including:

  * The things that we've provided or you've purchased;
  * When and where you've made the purchases;
  * What you paid and how;
  * Whether you've opened electronic communications from us;
  * Whether you've clicked on links in electronic communications from us.

| 

We use this information, including to:

  * Develop new products and services;
  * Improve our products and services;
  * Personalise our products and service;
  * Identify products and marketing that may be of interest to you;
  * Statistical analysis and research.

3 | 

Information when you communicate with us whether in person, through our website or via email, over the phone, through social media or via any other medium, including:

  * Your contact details (this may include your social media account if that's the way you communicate with us);
  * The details of your communications with us (including call recordings);
  * The details of our messages to you.

| 

We use this information, including to:

  * Answer any issues or concerns;
  * Monitor customer communications for quality and training purposes;
  * Develop new products and services;
  * Improve our products and services;
  * Personalise our products and services;
  * Regulatory compliance;

4 | 

Information that we collect through your use of our website including:

  * Device information such as operating system, unique device identifiers, the mobile network system;
  * Hardware and browser settings;
  * Date and time of requests;
  * The requests you make;
  * The pages you visit and search engine terms you use;
  * IP address.

| 

We use this information, including to:

  * Provide our products and services;
  * Develop new products and services;
  * Improve our products and services;
  * Personalise our products and services;
  * Identify issues with the website and user's experience of it;
  * Manage and administer our systems;
  * Monitor the way our website is used.

5 | 

Information that we collect incidentally from other sources or public sources, including:

  * Information available in the media;
  * Information presented on our social media timelines;
  * Information collected by security systems;
  * Information received from credit reference agencies.

| 

We use this information, including to:

  * Maintain market awareness;
  * Build and maintain social media branding;
  * Provide security to our sites;
  * Fraud prevention and confirming your identity.

Homebase does not knowingly collect data from any unsupervised person under the age of 18. If you are under the age of 18, you must not use the Homebase website or submit any personal data to us unless you have the consent of, and are supervised by, a parent or guardian.

**Why we collect your information**

We collect and use your information for a variety of reasons. We need some information to enter into and perform our contract – for example your contact and payment details.

Some information processing is required by law due to our anti-fraud screening obligations (please see the section on Legal requirements below) or in the public interest such as making sure we verify our customers' identities.

Some information is processed because you've given your consent. You can always unsubscribe from marketing communications.

Other information we collect because we have legitimate business interests, for example, in:

  * Understanding how you use our products, services and website;
  * Understanding and responding to your feedback;
  * Researching and analysing the services you want;
  * Improving our products and services;
  * Understanding the type of products you buy and how you use them;
  * Personalise our offers so we're better able to provide offers and ideas that are relevant to you;
  * Maintaining a public profile on both traditional and social media; or
  * Developing and maintaining relationships with vendors, partners and other companies and dealing with individuals who work for them.

**Other uses**

**Legal requirements**

Your personal information may also be processed if it is necessary on reasonable request by a law enforcement or regulatory authority, body or agency or in the defence of a legal claims. We will not delete personal information if relevant to an investigation or a dispute. It will continue to be stored until those issues are fully resolved.

**How long we keep your information**

We will keep your information for as long as it is reasonably necessary. It will depend on factors such as whether you have any outstanding purchases or an account with us or have interacted with recent offers. 

**Information we share**

There are certain circumstances where we may transfer your personal data to employees, contractors and to other parties.

  * We may share information about you with other members of our group of companies so we can provide the best service across our group. They are bound to keep your information in accordance with this privacy policy.
  * We may also share your information with certain contractors or service providers who assist us in the provision of products and services we supply to you, are involved in prize draws and competitions we run or provide other services to assist with our day to day operations. They may process your personal data for us, for example, if we use a marketing agency. Other recipient’s/service providers include manufacturers, logistics/delivery providers, advertising agencies, IT specialists, database providers, backup and disaster recovery specialists or email providers.

Our suppliers and service providers will be required to meet our standards on processing information and security. The information we provide them, including your information, will only be provided in connection with the performance of their function.

  * We may also share your information with certain third parties. We will do this either when we receive your consent or because we need them to see your information to provide products or services to you. These include credit reference agencies, anti-fraud databases, screening agencies and other partners we do business with. 

Your personal information may be transferred to other third party organisations in certain scenarios:

  * If we're discussing selling or transferring part or all of our business – the information may be transferred to prospective purchasers under suitable terms as to confidentiality;
  * If we are reorganised or sold, information may be transferred to a buyer who can continue to provide services to you;
  * If we're required to by law, or under any regulatory code or practice we follow, or if we are asked by any public or regulatory authority – for example the Police;
  * If we are defending a legal claim your information may be transferred as required in connection with defending such claim.

Your personal data may be shared if it is made anonymous and aggregated, as in such circumstances the information will cease to be personal data.

**Where your information will be held**  

We will only transfer data to jurisdictions outside the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) where the appropriate safeguards set out in the GDPR are in place.

We are happy to provide you with copies of the regulator-approved standard contractual clauses, which you can request from us using the contact details below.

#### 3 - Your rights

**Data Subject Rights**

We've listed the rights you have over your information and how you can use them below.

These rights will only apply in certain circumstances. Some of these rights will not be available if there are outstanding contracts between us, if we are required by law to keep the information or if the information is relevant to a legal dispute.

We will normally respond to or action (as applicable) requests within one month from receipt of your request. This period may be extended by 2 further months if necessary taking into account the complexity or number of requests. If this is the case, we will let you know within one month of your original request.

In general, the information or action requested will be provided free of charge. However, if requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive (or repetitive in nature) we may charge a fee (or alternatively refuse to deal with the request).

It is important that we establish that the individual right is being exercised by the correct person. Therefore, we may need to ask you for information in order to verify your identity prior to processing your request. This may include asking you to confirm certain details we hold about you (such as post code or first line of your address) or to provide proof of identification.

You have the right to make the following types of request regarding the personal data Homebase holds about you:

  * Right of access (subject access requests) – the right to request a copy of the personal data (if any) that we have concerning you and supporting information explaining how your personal data is used.
  * Right of rectification – the right to request that we rectify inaccurate or incomplete personal data concerning you.
  * Right of erasure (right to be forgotten) – the right, in some situations, to request that we transmit your data to you or another entity.
  * Right to restrict processing – the right, in some situations, to request that we do not use the personal data you have provided (e.g. if you believe it to be inaccurate). This is intended as a temporary right until the reason for such restriction has been resolved or rectified.
  * Right to data portability – the right, in some situations, to request that we transmit your data to you or another entity.
  * Right to object - the right to object to certain processing of your personal data (unless we have overriding compelling grounds to continue the processing) and the right to object to direct marketing/profiling In certain circumstances, we will be exempted from responding to certain requests. We will use these exemptions to the extent appropriate.

#### 4 - Contact us

**How to contact us**

If you have any questions about this policy please contact our Legal team at Data.Protection@homebase.co.uk, or by writing to Head of Legal, HHGL, Witan Gate House, 500-600 Witan Gate, Central Milton Keynes, MK9 1BA.

**Want to be removed from the Homebase direct marketing list?**

If you want to be removed from our email mailing list, [click here](https://homebaselife.com/public/m/unsubscribe) to use our unsubscribe form and put in the email address that you wish to be removed. In addition, each email we send you will contain details of how you can unsubscribe.

#### 5 - Changes to the policy

This policy may be changed from time to time and will be posted here. We encourage you to visit this area frequently to stay updated.

#### 6 - Other policies

**Cookies**

Our website uses cookies which are text files which contain small amounts of information that a website can send to, and store on, your computer or device through your browser. Cookies may be used by us to provide you with, for example, customised information from our website to make our website more user-friendly. This may include, for example, remembering your postcode for you so you don’t have to re-enter it every time you check the stock levels for an item you are interested in.

In addition, cookies allow us to understand who has seen which pages and advertisements, to determine how frequently particular pages are visited and to determine the most popular areas of our website.

We are required to provide you with clear and comprehensive information about the cookies which we use on the site and to obtain your consent to the use of cookies. In order to comply with these requirements we have prepared a cookie policy setting out information about cookies, detailing the cookies we use and providing information on how to manage cookies on your computer.

By using the Homebase website and mobile website, you are agreeing to our cookie policy and consent to the use of cookies and similar technologies by us and our carefully selected third party partners as described in our cookie policy. If you do not agree to such use, please see the 'Managing your cookies' section for details on how to adjust your settings.

For more information about cookies, the types of cookies we use and how we use them please see our Cookie Policy.

**Security**

We are committed to keeping your personal information safe. We've got appropriate physical, technical and administrative measures in place to protect your information against accidental or unauthorised destruction, loss, access or alteration.
